Essentially,
说到底
your family hurt him first.
还是你们容家先对不起他的
I've got no complaints about him.
我对他没什么意见
I just worry that you two can't help
我只是怕你们两个人把持不住
exchanging love glances
在外人面前眉来眼去
so that others gossip about you.
落人口实罢了
When your sister sticks to him like a dog,
有你妹妹像守着肉骨头似的守着他
how do I dare?
我哪敢呀
Fine, fine.
好好好
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I shouldn't have described Fanglin as a dog.
不该说芳林是小狗
Don't you
你们俩
have a plan?
难道没有什么计划吗
Plan?
计划
Do you and Miss Feng have a plan?
你跟那位冯小姐有计划吗
Everyone thinks alike under the same case.
这种事啊 遇上谁都一样
We'll just enjoy ourselves as far as we can.
能快活几日是几日
Life is long and boring.
人生总是漫长而苦闷的
Why can't we have some fun?
还不准我们找些乐子
Some people noticed your affair.
外面已经有一些风声了
My father got wind of it.
传到了我爹那里
For your own good,
为了你自己好
you'd better restrain yourself.
还是收敛一点
What does that mean?
什么意思
Be seated.
坐
What exactly happened?
到底怎么回事啊
Hashimoto Shiori gave my father a photo
桥本诗织给了我爹一张照片
taken in the foyer of the hotel in Hangzhou.
是在杭州酒店的大堂里拍的
As for the man in the photo...
至于内容是什么
I guess you know it better than me.
我想你比我更清楚
Is he...?
那有拍到
Don't worry.
你放心吧
Only the sight of his back.
只拍到了男人的背影
Or why do you think
要不然你以为
he can still play mahjong with my father
他还能安安稳稳的
without any problem?
同我爹在那里打麻将吗
Your ex-girlfriend is quite a big trouble.
你这个旧情人也太麻烦了
What the heck!
搞什么嘛
In this case,
那既然如此
why didn't your father break off our engagement?
你爹还不去杜家退婚
Why does he pretend nothing happened?
还装得跟没事一样
Our families are
容杜两家
having important business cooperation.
现在正在生意合作的关键时候
My father won't fall out with your family.
我爹才舍不得和你家闹翻呢
If your family is disgraced,
要是让杜家丢了脸面
my father will lose this business.
这笔生意就黄了
After all,
毕竟儿子的婚姻
compared to great wealth,
同他的荣华富贵比起来
the marriage of his son is nothing.
算不了什么
What do you want, then?
那你怎么想
You know exactly
我怎么想啊
what I want.
你还不知道吗
I never agree on our engagement.
我从一开始就不同意订婚
What about you?
倒是你
Are you serious
你和杨秀成
with Yang Xiucheng?
是认真的吗
No, in the beginning.
一开始自然不是
But now...
不过现在
Maybe.
也许吧
Our engagement is a joke.
我们的婚约就是个笑话
Time to put an end to it.
也差不多是时候该结束了
Mr. Jiashang.
大少爷
Come on in.
进来
the mutton noodles you asked for.
这是你吩咐的做羊肉面
Have some noodles first.
先吃碗面吧
Let's talk later.
吃完再说
What's the smell?
这是什么味道
What's wrong?
怎么了
Lanxin?
兰馨
Are you all right?
没事吧
Yes.
没事
Maybe I had too much seafood at dinner.
可能是晚上海鲜吃多了
I don't feel very well now.
不太舒服
I'm going back home.
我先回去了
Say goodbye to your parents for me.
你帮我跟伯父伯母打声招呼吧
Let's talk later
退婚的事
about the annulment of our engagement.
我们找时间再说吧
Fine.
好
Let me drive you back.
我送你
Here comes Xiao Baoli!
肖宝丽来了
Come on!
快
Go.
你快去
- Miss Baoli.
宝丽小姐 看这边 这边
Miss Baoli,
宝丽小姐
how do you expect the box office of your new movie?
请问您对新电影的票房有什么估计吗
It's said that you and Miss Lin don't get along well on the set.
听说您跟林小姐在片场不和
Is that true?
是真的吗
What do you think of the movie?
能对影片说一下您的看法吗
I certainly expect a big box office.
我当然希望电影票房能大卖了
Miss Lin and I are good friends.
我和林小姐是好朋友
Why would we not get along well?
怎么会闹矛盾呢
Besides, Miss Lin is
再说林小姐
a senior movie actress.
也是电影界老前辈了
I've got a lot to learn from her.
我还有很多地方要向她学习呢
Mr. Song is a promising young man.
宋三少是年轻才俊
But we're just friends.
但我们只是朋友
Miss Xiao is my honored guest.
肖小姐可是我的贵宾啊
She'll cut the ribbon for me.
一会儿还要帮我剪彩呢
If you still stop her,
你们再拦着她不让她走的话
she'll miss the propitious time.
那可要错过良时了
Come on.
来
Miss Feng, every time I see you at the ball,
每次见冯小姐在舞会上
you're eating.
都是在吃呢
Mr. Wu.
伍少爷
Long time no see.
好久不见
Miss Feng, here I am.
先生 还有我呢
Fanghua?
芳桦
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
My father allowed me to come.
爹爹特批的
In celebration
为了庆祝
of the admission to McTyeire School for Girls,
我跟姐姐考上中西女塾
my sister and I are allowed to come and see the movie actress.
准我们过来看明星
Where's Fanglin?
芳林呢
She's over there with Jiashang.
大哥跟芳林他们在那边
Miss Feng,
冯小姐
here we meet again.
我们又见面了
Your dress seems
冯小姐这身裙子
to be made by the Polish tailor
看着像是四川西路那家
on West Sichuan Road.
波兰裁缝的手艺
Unexpectedly,
没有想到
since you left the Rong family,
冯小姐离开容家之后
you've been living a better life.
过得越发得好了
I borrowed the dress from a friend.
只是借来的裙子而已
It's not worth mentioning.
不值得一提的
Looks like you have many friends.
看来冯小姐朋友还挺多的
No wonder you wear different dresses
难怪每次见到冯小姐
every time I see you.
借的裙子都不重样
Isn't it good to have many friends?
朋友多一点不好吗
It is.
挺好的
Your new sweetheart and your ex-girlfriend are talking.
你的新欢和旧爱撞到一起了
Don't you go handle that?
你不去处理一下吗
Just go.
快去吧
I'm going to the Smoking Room for a cigarette.
我去吸烟室抽支烟
Miss Du,
杜小姐
the Smoking Room is full of men.
吸烟室都是男人
Let me have a cigarette with you in the west small salon.
我陪你去西侧的小沙龙抽一支吧
- Fanglin. - Mm?
芳林
Wait a moment, please.
稍等我一下
I'll be right back.
去去就来
Is that true?
是吗
- Jiashang. - Mm.
大哥
The unveiling ceremony will start momentarily.
揭幕仪式快开始了
Fanghua,
芳桦
Miss Hashimoto,
桥本小姐
shall we go?
我们先过去吧
- Mm. - Let's go.
走
Miss Feng,
先生
here we meet again.
我们又见面了
Your family is on bad terms with the Meng family.
你们容家跟孟家的关系并不太好
Why did you come to Meng Xu'an's party?
怎么会来孟绪安的酒会
I have something to tell Meng Xu'an.
我来找孟绪安谈事情
Fanglin and Fanghua want to have fun.
芳林和芳桦也想过来玩
By the way,
对了
do you remember the Gold Kylin?
你还记得之前那个金麒麟吗
It belongs to the Meng family.
它本来就属于孟家
But my father
结果从我爹那里
sold it.
流落了出去
I don't know what Meng Xu'an gets
也不知道孟绪安手里
on my father.
有我爹什么把柄
My father is desperate
我爹心急火燎的
to get back the Gold Kylin.
要把金麒麟找回去
News that the Hashimoto family owns the Gold Kylin
现在金麒麟在桥本家的消息
has got out.
走漏了出去
Meng Xu'an is impatient
孟家按捺不住
and he urges us to hurry.
催我们动作快点
The Hashimotos don't want to sell it?
桥本家依旧不肯割爱吗
Hashimoto Shozo doesn't want to sell it.
桥本正三他不肯
But someone else does.
可是别人肯啊
Hashimoto Shiori
桥本诗织
paid a private visit to my father,
私下拜会过我爹了
saying when I broke off my engagement,
说我只要退婚娶她
she would marry me
她就能带着金麒麟
with the Gold Kylin as her dowry.
嫁到容家
Miss Hashimoto is bold and careful.
桥本小姐胆大心细
It's very thoughtful of her.
做事周全
She will do great things.
是个做大事的人
What's your plan?
那你怎么打算
Will you marry her?
答应她吗
What?
怎么了
Do you care very much?
你很在意吗
The Gold Kylin
金麒麟
isn't my concern.
关我什么事啊
Wait.
等等
Here's something serious.
说正经的
I've got some information
你家的事情
about your family.
我这边查到了一点消息
I had my men ask around in Guojia Town.
我派人去郭家镇打探
There,
结果在镇里
they didn't find a Lady Bai
没有找到外出后
who got lost after leaving home.
失踪的白姓妇人
In the files of the police station,
巡捕房的卷宗里
no useful information was found, either.
也没有记载什么可用的消息
But they found out something else.
但是查到了另外一件事情
Shortly after the tragedy,
那桩惨案发生了没几天之后
a man reported to the police
就有一个人到巡捕房报案
that his little daughter fell into water
说自己的小女儿落水失踪
and her body was nowhere to be found.
找不到尸首
The police
巡捕房的人
told him
只说最近
no children's bodies had been found
没有入殓过孩童的尸体
and turned him away.
便把他打发了
So, there's no more information.
所以也没有留下他的信息
Mother!
妈妈
Shizhen,
世真
don't be nervous.
你别紧张
He may not be your family.
也不一定就是你的家人
I'll ask my men
我会派人
to track it down.
顺着这条线索查下去
Once they get any information,
一旦有什么消息
they'll let me know immediately.
他们会立即告诉我的
My mother was killed.
我娘都已经被杀了
Who would know I fell into water and got lost?
还有谁会知道我落水失踪的
It's him.
是他
The man who killed my mother.
是那个杀了我娘的人
He didn't find my body.
因为他没有看到我的尸首
So, he was asking around.
所以才会在附近到处打听
He may have known
他或许已经知道
that I was rescued.
我获救的消息
Don't worry.
别担心了
It happened 20 years ago.
这件事情都已经过去二十年了
If he knew you were still alive,
他要是知道
he would have come to you.
早就找上门了
Rest assured.
放心吧
Let's stop the investigation.
还是不查了
If it continues,
我怕这样查下去
I'm afraid that man will be alerted.
会打草惊蛇的
I'm using my men.
我用的都是我自己手下的人
They only take orders from me.
他们只听我吩咐
Even my father can't order them about.
我爹也使唤不了
I'll ask them to keep a low profile.
我会让他们低调行事
You won't be involved.
绝对不会牵扯到你
Anyway,
总之
I'll take care of everything.
一切有我
What?
怎么了
You miss me?
想我了
What can't you say in the hall?
有什么话不能在屋里说的
The hall is crowded.
屋里人多口杂
I have something to tell you.
我有个事要告诉你
Did...?
是
Did Rong Jiashang say anything?
容嘉上说什么了吗
It's not about him.
跟他没关系
Do you remember
你记得
that I took some medicine
咱们俩在杭州
when we were in Hangzhou?
我吃的那个药
You asked me if I was sick.
你问我是不是生病了
Is it harmful
那药
to your health?
对你身子不好
I don't know.
好不好我不知道
But during our first sex in the compartment of the train,
但是咱们第一次在火车车厢里
I didn't take the medicine.
我那次没准备
Are you sure about the pregnancy?
你确定吗
I saw a Chinese doctor and a western doctor.
中医西医都看了
They gave the same diagnosis.
全是一个说法
I'm pregnant for nearly one month.
算时间差不多就是一个月
I got it on the train to Hangzhou.
在去杭州的火车上
Who else
这事
knows it?
还有谁知道
Rong Jiashang, I guess.
容嘉上可能知道了
I felt unwell when I was in his home.
我那天在他家状态不太好
I think he figured it out.
我想他猜出来了
Lanxin, you...
兰馨 你
How could you...?
你怎么能
He knew about our relationship long ago.
他早就知道我们的关系了
He doesn't care at all.
他根本就不在乎
But...
不是
On the surface,
我现在至少在明面上
I can't break with the Rong family now.
我 我不能跟容家撕破脸
You know that.
这个你知道的
You're scared?
你害怕了
You lost your place in the Rong family long ago.
你在容家早就没有地位了
And you slept with Rong Jiashang's fiancée.
现在又睡了大少爷的女人
What?
怎么
Still want to be Rong Dingkun's lackey?
你想继续在容家做一条狗吗
If Rong Dingkun knows I betrayed him,
容定坤如果知道我背叛他
he wouldn't only beat me.
不是打一顿那么简单的
You...
你
You're the lady of the Du family.
你是杜家大小姐
He won't hurt you.
他不会动你
But in his eyes,
但是我在他眼里
I'm nothing.
什么都不是
You're the father of my baby.
但是你是我孩子的爹
Xiucheng,
秀成
you once told me
你曾经跟我说
that you wanted us to have a baby
想要跟我生个孩子
and a bright future.
想跟我有将来
Did you say that
难道只是为了哄我上床
only to sleep with me?
随口说说的吗
I didn't.
当然不是
It's just...
只是这一切让我
It's all very sudden.
这一切太突然了
I'm... I'm just not ready.
我 我还没准备好
If you want to stop
你要是觉得
and avoid bigger trouble,
玩大了想收手
I'll have an appointment with the western doctor
我明天就去预约西医
for an abortion.
做手术
Lanxin,
兰馨
I don't mean that.
我不是这个意思
We agreed from the begging
咱们一开始就说好了的
that we would break up if we didn't get along.
合则聚不合则分
I'm not a woman
我也不是那种离了男人
who can't live without a man.
就活不下去的女人
I just thought
只是原本我以为
we could struggle for our future.
我们可以试着搏一下的
If you get cold feet,
你要是想临阵退缩
just tell me in advance.
提前告诉我就行
Du Lanxin,
杜兰馨
what a loser you are!
你这个没出息的
Why did you fall for such a man?
最后竟然栽在这么一个男人身上
I'll answer for it.
我会负责的
Lanxin,
兰馨
give birth to the baby.
把孩子生下来
Let's be together
我们在一起
and bring him up.
一起把他养大
I'll take you away as soon as I can.
我会尽快带你走
♪Outside the long corridor♪
长亭外
♪Along the ancient road♪
古道边
♪The green grass seemed to connect with the sky♪
芳草碧连天
♪Under the gentle night breeze swung the willows and resonated the flute♪
晚风拂柳笛声残
♪Whilst the descending sun illuminated mountains by mountain♪
夕阳山外山
♪At the edge of the sky♪
天之涯
♪And the corner of the land♪
地之角
♪The friends in hearts have gone their separate ways♪
知交半零落
Who's that?
谁啊
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Sorry to disturb you.
打扰了
Who are you?
你是谁啊
I'm a guest from downstairs.
我就是楼下的一个客人
I'm a friend of Mr. Meng's.
七爷的朋友
Come on in.
请进
Did you
这些
draw the paintings?
都是你画的
You look quite familiar.
你看着好眼熟啊
Don't be nervous.
别紧张
Be seated, please.
请坐
Thank you.
谢谢
You look beautiful.
你长得好漂亮
Could you be my model?
你愿意做我的模特吗
Could you, Miss?
可以吗 姐姐
Sure.
可以
Don't move.
你别动啊
You must be familiar with my brother.
你应该和我大哥很熟吧
Brother?
大哥
Who's your brother?
请问令兄是
Meng Xu'an.
孟绪安
I'm the ninth child of my family.
我在家里排行第九
Oh, you're Xiaojiu?
原来是九少啊
Mr. Meng didn't tell me about me.
七爷之前没跟我提过你
Sorry for not recognizing you.
不好意思
Are you his girlfriend?
你是我大哥的女朋友吧
No.
不是
I work for him.
我只是为他做事的人
He likes you, I guess.
那他应该挺喜欢你的
You smell like him.
你身上有他的气息
It's done.
画好了
Come and have a look.
你过来看一下
All right.
好
Looks nice.
画得真不错
How long have you learned to paint?
九少学画画多长时间啊
Xiaojiu?
九少
No.
不对
Something's wrong.
这画不对
What's wrong?
哪里不对啊
Something's wrong. Wrong!
不对
Xiaojiu...
九少
It's wrong.
不是这样的
Are you all right?
你没事吧
Did I scare you?
我吓着你了吗
Don't be scared.
别怕
Help me up.
扶我起来
Shall I ask someone to take care of you?
我叫人来照顾你吧
I feel dizzy.
我头晕
Help me up
你扶我起来
and I won't tell my brother
我就不告诉大哥今天
you broke into my room.
你闯进我画室的事情
Come on.
快
Help me up.
扶我一下
I'll tell you a story.
我给你讲个故事
Xiaojiu!
小九
- Let go of me! - Xiaojiu.
放开我
Ask the doctor to inject him.
找医生
- Go. - Let go of me!
给小九打一针
Let go of me!
放开我
Be gentle to him!
轻一点
Mr. Meng, I...
七爷 我
Come with me.
你跟我过来
Come.
过来
I'm sorry, Mr. Meng.
七爷
I didn't mean that.
我不是故意的
Xiaojiu said he wanted to portray me.
九少他跟我说要给我作画
I didn't expect him to...
我没有想到他突然
I'm sorry.
对不起
You know who he is?
你知道他是谁
I don't know.
我不知道
He told me about his identity.
是他自己说的
Mr. Meng,
七爷
I broke into that room accidentally.
我是无意间进了那个房间
I was even unaware of his existence.
我之前都不知道这个人的存在
But now you're aware.
可你现在知道了
Mr. Meng, don't worry.
七爷放心
I don't have a loose tongue.
我不是口舌不严的人
I won't tell anyone about him.
我不会把这件事情说出去的
It doesn't matter.
无所谓
It won't be long
过不了多久
before everyone in Shanghai knows about him.
整个上海滩都会知道他的存在
I'll pretend I didn't see him.
我会当这件事情没有发生过的
Shizhen,
世真
you're never a busybody.
你一直都不爱多管闲事
It's good for you.
这是个好习惯
I know.
我知道
By the way,
对了
Rong Jiashang just told me
刚才容嘉上跟我说
that Hashimoto Shiori wanted
桥本诗织
to replace Du Lanxin
有意挤掉杜兰馨
and marry him with the Gold Kylin.
带着金麒麟嫁给他
Your man is quite popular
你这个容嘉上啊
with girls.
还真是炙手可热
But he didn't tell you the whole story.
不过他没有把话说完
It can't be
这笔交易
simply a marriage
绝对不仅仅是
between him and a woman.
一桩婚事这么简单
I'll keep an eye on it.
我会留意的
Take action accordingly.
你自己看着办吧
By the way,
对了
stay away from my brother.
离我弟弟远一点
Next time, he may hold something worse
下次他手里拿的
than a painting knife.
或许就不是画刀了
Keep that in mind.
记住
Fanglin?
芳林
Why are you here alone?
你怎么自己在这啊
What happened?
出什么事了
Who bullied you?
谁欺负你了
If something upsets you,
有什么不开心的事
tell me about it.
你可以跟我说
I'll keep the secret for you.
我会帮你保守秘密的
Miss Feng,
先生
why does a woman
你说在这个世界上
like someone else
为什么有人订了婚
even when she's engaged?
她还喜欢别人啊
Tang Xianzu once said
汤显祖老人家不是也说过吗
that love once begun
情不知所起
would never end.
一往而深
In terms of love,
感情这种事情啊
we can't control ourselves.
自己是没有办法控制的
That's why there are so many sad love stories.
所以才会有那么多的悲欢离合啊
Maybe
这可能
it's the charm of love.
也是爱情迷人之处吧
What is love?
那爱情是什么呀
Love...
爱情
It's luck, I guess.
我想是幸运吧
In a man's life,
人这一生当中
when he has the most heartfelt love,
如果能遇到那份最真挚的情感
even if it doesn't end up well,
就算不能得偿所愿
it'll be his great luck.
也是人生大幸
Is it because of luck
是幸运
that they did that kind of thing?
所以他们才会那样的吗
Perhaps.
也许吧
Don't be sad.
别难受了
In the future,
你以后
you'll have your own luck.
也一定会遇到这份幸运的
Something's wrong. Wrong!
不对
Did I scare you?
我吓着你了吧
Why does Xiaojiu look so familiar?
孟九怎么这么眼熟
Have I met him before?
我是在哪见过
Or...
还是
Does he look like someone?
长相上
According to the newspaper,
这报上说
(Central China Antique Charity Auction) On the 22nd of this month,
本月二十二日
there'll be a charity auction in the Museum.
在市博物馆举行一场慈善拍卖会
Your good friend Miss Xiao will cut the ribbon.
你那个好朋友肖小姐要去剪彩
Is that so?
是吗
What kind of auction can be so grand?
什么拍卖会这么隆重啊
It's a charity auction
这是文物界啊
held for soldiers on the frontline and dependents of martyrs
为前线的将士和烈士家属
by the cultural relics circle.
举行的一场慈善募捐
Many precious antiques will be auctioned.
很多珍贵的拍品要进行拍卖
A mysterious antique won't be shown
还说了有一件神秘的拍品
until the auction starts.
要在现场才会揭晓
Rich men have got a lot of ideas.
这有钱人的把戏是真多
Then again,
不过话又说回来
it's quite a big auction.
这次拍卖会的阵仗可真不小
Many celebrities of cultural relics will attend it.
很多文物界的名人要参加
Look.
这
Rong Dingkun will attend it, too.
容定坤也要去啊
All celebrities of Shanghai
这不是全上海的
will meet there, right?
这些名流都要凑到一起去了
Some Japanese will attend it, too.
还有日本人
Apparently,
这不用说
they attend the auction for our cultural relics.
这一看就是冲着咱们的文物去的
Think about the Japanese.
你说这些日本人
They run factories everywhere
到处开设工厂
and exploit the workers.
盘剥咱们的工人
On the black market,
还在黑市上
they even buy a lot of antiques.
大肆收购咱们的古玩
When I think
我这一想到咱们的国宝
that foreigners will have our national treasure,
就要落到外国人的手里面
I...
我
I feel so hurt.
我就心痛啊 我
Civilians like us can't interfere with that.
这也不是我们平头百姓能管得了的
I'm warning you.
我跟你讲啊
You can only talk like that at home.
你呀这些话就是在家说说就好了
Don't talk nonsense out of our home.
千万不要到外面胡说八道
Do you hear me?
你听见没有啊
I get it.
我知道啊
Father,
爹
show me the newspaper.
报纸给我看看
It won't be long
过不了多久
before everyone in Shanghai knows about him.
整个上海滩都会知道他的存在
Will Mr. Meng do something
难道七爷打算在
at the auction?
拍卖会上做些什么
It's a copy?
这是仿制的
Yes.
对
Zhu Laojiu has great craftsmanship.
朱老九手艺极高
I checked it carefully.
我仔细检查过了
There's no problem with it, I believe.
应该不会有什么问题
It's nearly a perfect copy.
这仿制的水平可真不错呀
But the Gold Kylin is the heirloom of the Meng family.
不过这金麒麟是孟家的传家之宝
You think Meng Xu'an can't recognize it?
孟绪安会发现不了
Don't worry.
您放心吧
I won't give it to Meng Xu'an.
我不会把它交给孟绪安的
What will you do, then?
你打算怎么办
I'll have it sent
我会找人
to the auction site
把它送到拍卖会上
for an anonymous auction.
匿名竞拍
Auction?
竞拍
By then, Meng Xu'an and Hashimoto Shozo
届时孟绪安和桥本正三
will be at the auction.
都会到会场
When they see the Gold Kylin
他们在会场上
be auctioned,
看到这个金麒麟
how will they react?
会做何反应
There's fun to see.
一场好戏
By the way,
对了
Father,
爹
after the auction is over
等到拍卖会结束
and the Gold Kylin problem is solved,
金麒麟事了
I will request the Du family
我会向杜家
to break off the engagement.
提出解除婚约
Be right there.
来了
Shizhen?
世真
Baoli.
宝丽
What brings you here?
你怎么来了
Be seated.
快坐
All right.
好
- Baoli. - Mm?
宝丽
May I ask you for a favor?
有个事情想找你帮忙
My pleasure.
我们之间还客气什么
What is it?
说
In the newspaper,
我看报纸上说
I read about a charity auction next week
下个礼拜有个慈善拍卖会
that you'll cut the ribbon for.
说你要去剪彩
I want to attend it.
我就想说
Could you take me there
你看能不能把我也带进去
as your assistant?
让我做你的助理
I know you don't like
要不是知道你平时
balls or parties.
不爱参加什么舞会酒会的
Otherwise,
像这样的场合
I would have taken you
我都不知道
to such occasions many times.
想带你去参加多少回了
Don't worry.
你放心吧
You're the best, Baoli.
宝丽最好了
You seldom
还真难得
want to attend such an auction.
你有这份孝心啊
Mr. Meng?
七爷
By the way,
对了
Baoli has to go with the leading actor.
宝丽要给男主角做女伴
Why don't you
要不然
be my companion?
你做我的女伴如何
Good idea.
这个主意好
- Baoli. - Mm?
宝丽
I'm a little bit hungry.
我有些饿了
Fine.
好
Wait a minute.
稍等一下
In my home,
之前
I said something to you.
我在家里跟你说的那些话
Do you still remember?
你还记得吗
Yes.
记得
You asked me not to be smart.
七爷叫我不要自作聪明
Looks like you have no problem
看来你听力
with your listening or memory.
记性都没问题
You just
就是
don't like to follow my order.
不喜欢照着做
I don't understand, Mr. Meng.
我不懂七爷是什么意思
You came in the middle of the night,
大半夜的
asking Baoli for a favor
主动上门托情
because you didn't want me to know it.
无非就是不想让我知道
If I guess correctly,
要是我没有猜错的话
it's not the antiques
对于这个拍卖会
at the auction
你感兴趣的
that you're interested in.
想来不是那些古董
I'm just worried.
我只是不放心
About what?
不放心什么
Rong Jiashang?
容嘉上
You fear that he'll get in trouble?
你怕他出什么事情吗
I hope he'll get in no trouble.
最好什么事情也别出
I don't think he'll feel grateful.
可他未必领情
What?
怎么样
Have you made a deal?
你们定好了吗
Yes.
说定了
I'll listen to Mr. Meng.
都听七爷的
By the way,
对了七爷
I'm afraid it's too late
现在给世真做一条裙子
to make a dress for Shizhen.
怕是来不及了
Yesterday, I got a new dress.
昨天我刚好收到一条新的
By then,
到时候啊
Shizhen can try it on.
可以给世真试试
Thank you, Baoli.
谢谢宝丽
Mr. Meng,
七爷
you'll take her to the ball.
您都要带人家去参加舞会了
You won't let her go without a necklace, will you?
总不能让人空着脖子去吧
How about this?
这样吧
Tomorrow,
明天
I'll ask salesgirls of Printemps
我让巴黎春天的售货员
to bring you some jewels
带一些珠宝过来
to pick from.
然后你们挑一挑
All right.
好啊
That's more like it.
这还差不多
Will you really take Taichi there?
你真的要让太一一起去
Shiori reminded me.
还是诗织提醒了我
At the auction,
这次的拍卖会
celebrities of Shanghai will gather.
聚集了全上海的名流
Young men and ladies
各家公子小姐
will attend it.
都会出席
Taichi is
太一啊
old enough to get married.
也到了婚配的年龄
I'd like to take him there.
不如让他去看看
If he takes a fancy to a lady,
万一要相中哪家小姐
we can propose marriage to her family.
我们也好提亲
Yeah.
是呀
I think Taichi is getting better lately.
我看哥哥近来身体好了些
He can go out for some fun.
可以出去走走
You make sense,
话虽如此
but Taichi is sick.
但太一这个病
He has to be taken care of.
身边少不了人照顾
Well...
那
Shall I go
要不
and take care of him?
我去跟着照顾哥哥吧
Don't worry.
你们放心
I'll take good care of him.
我一定会把哥哥照顾好的
Good idea.
也好啊
Go with us, then.
那就一起去吧
Shiori.
姐
Is everything ready?
都准备好了吗
Rest assured, Shiori.
姐姐你放心
I'll get it done perfectly.
我一定把事办好
Hope so.
最好是
It concerns our future.
这事关系着我们俩的未来
You'd better let nothing go wrong.
你最好做到万无一失
Fine, fine.
行了行了 你把心放在肚子里吧
Your daughters are pretty.
令嫒生得真的是俊俏大方
Coincidentally,
正巧
my son Taichi doesn't have a girl.
今天太一
Shall we make them companions
不如两个年轻人搭个伴
in case they get bored?
省得无聊
Fanglin, go ahead.
芳林啊
Young guys like you
年轻人嘛
should make more friends.
就应该多交朋友
Nice to meet you, Miss Rong.
幸会 容小姐
Nice to meet you.
你好
Mr. Rong.
容老板
Do you know there'll be a mystery antique for today's auction?
可知今晚有一个神秘的拍品
I've heard about it.
略有耳闻
They keep it very secret.
看他们今天这个保密的样子
It must be a rare treasure.
想必是一件非常稀奇的宝物啊
If it's something precious,
若是好东西
hope you'll show mercy in the bidding.
还望容老板手下留情啊
You flatter me.
哪里 哪里
If you want something,
桥本先生看上的东西
I won't make bids at all.
我容某必会拱手相让
Mr. Meng,
孟老板
I didn't expect you to come.
没想到你也会来
I only dabble
我对这个古董啊
in antiques.
也是有一点点涉猎罢了
I just come to have a look
今天过来掌掌眼的
when I can also cheer
顺便为前线将士
for soldiers on the frontline.
加加油 打打气
It's modest of you, Xu'an.
绪安老弟真是太谦虚了
Miss Feng,
冯小姐
nice to meet you again.
我们又见面了
Shiori,
诗织
who is this lady?
这位小姐是
I neglected to introduce her.
忘了介绍
Miss Feng used to be
冯先生呀 她先前是
Fanglin and Fanghua's governess.
芳林和芳桦的家庭教师
We met a couple of times in Rong's Residence.
在容家的时候我们见过几面
Hello, Miss Feng.
先生好
Miss Feng.
先生
You two look gorgeous.
你们俩今天可真漂亮
So do you, Miss Feng.
先生你也漂亮
You don't have a companion?
没有男伴吗
I do. Yuchi is my companion.
有 云驰哥陪我的
He's away because he met his teacher.
不过刚才遇到他的师长了
This is Mr. Hashimoto Taichi, Fanglin's companion.
姐姐的男伴是这位桥本太一先生
Nice to meet you.
你好
Miss Feng,
先生
did you come with Mr. Meng?
您今天是同孟老板一道来的吗
I'm curious, too.
我也在好奇呢
Miss Feng, when did you get so familiar
什么时候冯小姐
with Mr. Meng?
同孟老板这么熟了
When my female friends
我的那些女友们
talked about today's auction,
谈论起今日的拍卖会
they wondered
都在猜
which lady would come with Mr. Meng.
孟老板会带哪位女士一起
I didn't expect it
没想到
to be Miss Feng.
居然是冯小姐
Miss Feng is Xiao Baoli's friend.
冯先生不是认识肖宝丽吗
She then got to know Mr. Meng.
通过她顺理成章认识孟老板的
Mr. Pei asked me
我也是受裴先生所托啊
to take care of my junior.
照顾照顾这个小师妹
You have no idea.
各位有所不知
Before I studied in the United States,
我在去美国上学之前
I was a student of Mr. Pei's.
是在裴先生手下念书的
When I came back and visited him,
回来看老先生才知道
I got to know
原来冯小姐
Miss Feng was a student of his, too.
也在裴先生手下念书
So,
所以
she's my junior.
自然就是小师妹了
You two are quite destined to meet.
那你们二位可真有缘啊
Jiashang,
嘉上
Miss Feng is your governess.
冯小姐是你的老师
In this case,
那这么算来
isn't Mr. Meng your senior uncle?
孟先生不就是你的师叔了
I'm an ignorant man.
我是不学无术啊
I don't dare
这么大个便宜
to take advantage of Mr. Jiashang.
我可不敢占
The auction is about to begin.
里面差不多了
Let's get in.
进去吧
Let's go.
走
Come on.
来
Distinguished guests,
尊敬的各位来宾
ladies and gentlemen,
女士们 先生们
thank you for coming
欢迎各位今日莅临现场
to the charity auction
来参加由鲁意斯摩拍卖公司
held by Ruismo Auction Company.
举办的慈善拍卖会
Money from auctions will be donated
今日拍卖所得
(Central China Antique Charity Auction) to soldiers on the frontline
将全部捐献给前线的将士
(Ruismo Auction Company) and dependents of martyrs.
和烈士的家属
Today, we have six items.
今日共有六件拍卖品
Half an hour for each one.
每半个小时拍卖一件
For the rest of the time,
其余时间
hope you will
还请诸位
have a good time.
吃好玩好
Do enjoy yourselves.
务必尽兴
- All right.
好 好 好
Here.
好啊
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you. There.
谢谢 好嘞
Thanks.
多谢
I declare
我宣布
Ruismo Auction
鲁意斯摩慈善拍卖会
officially opens.
正式开始
Let's have the famous movie star Miss Xiao Baoli
欢迎著名影星肖宝丽小姐
to present you the first item.
为我们开启第一件拍品
It is
这一件拍品
a pigeon-blood ruby necklace.
是鸽血红宝石项链
We start the bidding at 500 silver dollars.
起价五百大洋
Make your bids, please.
请诸位开始叫价
All right.
好
550 silver dollars over here.
这位先生出价五百五十块
600 silver dollars from No. 23.
二十三号先生出价六百
700 over there.
好 七百
800 from No. 14.
好 十四号先生出价八百块
800 going once.
八百块 一次
800 going twice.
八百 两次
1,000.
一千
1,000 from No. 16.
十六号先生出价一千
You're fair-skinned.
你皮肤白
The ruby necklace suits you very well.
这个红宝石很适合你
Do I hear a higher bid?
还有没有出价的
Mr. Meng is quite wealthy.
孟老板可真是财大气粗
He's just throwing money.
拿钱砸着听响呢
1,000 going once.
一千一次
Going twice.
两次
1,200.
一千二
1,200 from No. 7.
七号先生出价一千二
But I don't like this necklace.
我可不喜欢这条链子
1,300 from No. 17.
十七号先生出价一千三
I never say
我可没有说过
I'll get it for you.
要拍下来送给你啊
1,300.
一千三
Do I hear a higher bid?
还有没有加价的
Are you getting back at me for my sarcasm just now?
你是在报复我刚才挖苦你吗
1,300 going once.
一千三 第一次
I'm not that narrow-minded.
我可没有这么小心眼
I just want to warn you.
我只是想警告你
Whatever you're thinking of,
无论你在想什么
never try to provoke my girl again.
都别再挑衅我的女人
1,300 going twice.
一千三 第二次
1,500.
一千五